So here is a quick lecture
Đây là bài giảng nhanh
on the service named AWS Cost Anomaly Detection.
về dịch vụ AWS Cost Anomaly Detection.
And the name is quite explicit this time.
Tên của nó lần này khá rõ ràng.
So this continuously monitors your cost and usage data,
Nó liên tục giám sát dữ liệu chi phí và sử dụng của bạn,
and it will use machine learning to detect unusual spends.
và dùng machine learning để phát hiện chi tiêu bất thường.
So it's going to learn from you.
Nó sẽ học từ bạn.
It's going to learn your unique historical patterns,
Học các mẫu lịch sử riêng của bạn,
and then it will detect one-time cost spikes
rồi phát hiện các đột biến chi phí
and/or continuous cost increases.
hoặc các khoản tăng chi phí liên tục.
And you don't have to define anything,
Bạn không phải định nghĩa gì cả,
you don't have to define thresholds.
không cần đặt ngưỡng.
It just knows on its own what looks a little bit weird.
Nó tự biết điều gì trông hơi lạ.
So it's going to monitor for your AWS services,
Nó sẽ giám sát các dịch vụ AWS,
your member accounts, your cost allocation tags,
các tài khoản thành viên, cost allocation tag
and your cost categories.
và cost categories của bạn.
And it will send you an anomaly detection report
Nó sẽ gửi báo cáo phát hiện bất thường
with the root cause analysis
với phân tích nguyên nhân gốc
of what is happening in your account.
về những gì đang diễn ra trong tài khoản của bạn.
You can get notified by either using individual alerts
Bạn có thể được thông báo bằng alert riêng lẻ
or a daily or weekly summary that leverages SNS.
hoặc bản tóm tắt hằng ngày hay hằng tuần qua SNS.
So to summarize, using machine learning,
Tóm lại, dùng machine learning,
you can have a look at your cost,
bạn có thể xem chi phí của mình,
you can get alerted and quickly analyze the root cause,
được cảnh báo và nhanh chóng phân tích nguyên nhân,
all of using the AWS cost anomaly detection service.
tất cả nhờ dịch vụ AWS Cost Anomaly Detection.
Okay, that's it.
Được rồi, hết rồi.
I hope you liked it,
Hy vọng bạn thích,
and I will see you in the next lecture.
và hẹn gặp lại ở bài tiếp theo.